Okay, in this video then, we are going to
talk about SWAT analysis.
Now, generally, we tend
to think of SWAT as more of
a strategic and business
management type of activity.
And it's something that is done by senior
management.
Yes, that is absolutely correct.
However, SWAT can also be done in many,
many different areas.
And in this case, we're talking about SWAT
analysis as it pertains to your team.
Now, what stands for?
Strengths, weaknesses, opportunities,
and threats.
So you're identifying the strengths,
you're identifying weaknesses.
And then see how they play against
opportunities, which are positive risks,
and threats, which are negative risks.
And we're going to talk about risk in a
completely separate section.
There's an entire lesson, entire knowledge
area on risk management.
Now, the whole idea behind this is to
basically understand the skills and comfort.
of your team.
In this case, that's what analysis then
you are analyzing the capabilities of your
team, right, pinpointing areas of
improvement, by basically recognizing any
training needs or, you know, any other
areas of improvement there and basically
making sure we are using our team
efficiently.
And essentially what I
want to do is we want
to organize our teams
around their strengths.
Right, so you're going to be identifying
the strengths of your team, identifying
weaknesses, So strengths such as,
you know, technical skills and,
you know, other skill sets, weaknesses,
you know, what we're lacking, right?
So, you know, we're lacking some team
members are lacking some skills.
Maybe they need to go on an additional
training.
Or even something like team members are
not getting along.
So how do we need to improve that?
There's a gap there.
If team members are
not getting along, then
you're not going to make a very good team.
We need team members to get along.
We need team members to work together.
Right.
So how do we feel?
fill that gap, right?
So that's what one of these, you know,
you could do a SWAT analysis for that.
So strength then,
identifying, again, what gives
your team a competitive
advantage, weaknesses, right?
So what gaps are there?
Opportunities, what external conditions
are there, or even internal conditions,
right, for growth, and then threats,
right?
Negative risks that could impact or
negatively impact your project.
And the whole principle behind this,
right, team skill appraisal, right,
team skill appraisal, which
we covered in a separate
video, basically, you're
going to be negotiating.
Team members are going to be negotiating
their roles, right?
You're going to be placing team members in
different roles, right?
So you're going to be negotiating all
that.
So you're going to be placing team members
based on their strengths and weaknesses.
And, I mean, to some extent you do that
all the time anyway, but, you know,
some people are technical, Some people are
introverts.
Some people are sociable.
So you want to put the right people in the
right role.
Some strive in a stressful environment.
Some don't strive in a stressful
environment.
So let me just give you a very simple
analogy here.
Now, this is going to
sound very obvious, but it
applies to every single
organizational situation.
So let's say, for example, you're a
restaurant owner.
You want to hire a chef.
You want to hire a chef so that they can
cook the meals for your restaurant,
right, for your customers.
So you, you know, you see the resumes and,
you know, you've got some really good,
strong candidates, you interview them and
then you hire them.
You're going to hire a chef to work in the
kitchen.
You are not hiring this chef to wait on
tables.
You're hiring the chef to work on the
kitchen.
That's their strength.
Their strengths is not waiting on tables.
And then you're hiring
other team members, you're
hiring other employees
to wait on tables, right?
You're not going to hire them.
If they've got skill sets, their skill set
is waiting on tables.
You're not going to hire them to cook a
meal in the kitchen for your customers.
You're going to hire the right people.
So remember, in any
project, you need to have
the right people with
the right skill sets.
But I should really expand that.
You want to hire the
right people, the right
skill sets, and put
them in the right role.
So the example I just gave, I mean,
it sounds very obvious, but that should
apply to every single organizational
situation.
And then that should apply to your project
as well.
We want the right people with the right
skill sets, right?
And we want to put them in the right role,
and we need them to be working.
together.
And then the SWAT analysis then that can
help identify that.
That will help identify strengths and
weaknesses, identify, you know,
aspirations of team members, where they
want to go, what kind of opportunities are
there for team member, for team growth,
right?
And then also what potential threats are
out there for team growth.
And a very simple example.
More recently of, you
know, that that could lack
or that that could have
hindered team growth.
growth was this whole COVID situation.
In beginning of 2020, when the COVID
situation came about, right, there was
obviously, you know,
a lot of uncertainty and,
you know, a lot of projects got cancelled.
That was a huge uncertainty.
That was a huge threat, if you like, or a
huge risk for, you know,
for team development.
Just a very, very simple example.
But again, you could be identifying all of
these.
What are the opportunities for team
development?
What are the the threats, what are the
risks, negative risk for team development?
Okay.